Guide to the Ester Hernandez Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Public Relations, Series 7; 1 linear ft.
  - Top of the Arts, - 50 San Francisco Arts Leaders: SF Live, February, 1996 (Box 71, Folder 15)
  - Galeria de la Raza 25th Anniversary (Box 71, Folder 16)
  - "Chicago Heritage is All of Ours - Ester Hernandez Gives Us the Art of Provocation," newspaper article, 1995 (Box 71, Folder 17)
  - "The Art of Provocation - Ester Hernandez - a Retrospective," Cn Gorman museum, UC Davis, brochure, 1995 (Box 71, Folder 18)
  - La Exposicion Chicana en el MAM [Museo de Arte Moderno, Mexico City]; news article, November, 1993 (Box 71, Folder 19)
  - Art del Otro Mexico, Mexican Museum, Chicago, 1993-1995 (Box 71, Folder 20)
  - The Power of Feminist Art: excerpt from book, 1994 (Box 71, Folder 21)
  - Ceremony of Spirit, The Mexican Museum, San Francisco, CA (Box 71, Folder 22)
  - "Discovering Cesar Chavez's true legacy," newspaper article, SF Examiner, 4/29/1993; reprint, 9/1994 (Box 71, Folder 23)
  - "Cesar Chavez Nurtured Seeds of Art," newspaper article, LA Times, 4/28/1993 (Box 71, Folder 24)
  - "The Fifith Element: Recent Acquisitions of Contemporary Chicano Art," Mexican Museum, San Francisco, 1992-1993 (Box 71, Folder 25)
  - CARA [Chicano Art: Resistance and Affirmation] - San Antonio, TX, 1993: newsletter, news article (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Pasion Por Frida, The Mexican Cultural Institute of New York, presented by National Institute of Fine Arts of Mexico, 1992 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - "Harlequin Fantasies and a Visionary Chicano Art Show," newspaper article, SF Chronicle,1/2/1993 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - "We Have a Beautiful Mother," Alice Walker poem accompanied by Hernandez's "Mis Madres," in Equal Means magazine, Summer, 1992 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - CARA [Chicano Art: Resistance and Affirmation] Wright Art Gallery, UCLA, 1991 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Heroes and Saints, by Cherrie Moraga, play announcement, San Francisco, 1992 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - "A Call to Social Action: The Art of Ester Hernandez:" reprint from Shaman's Drum Arts Gallery Magazine, Brekeley, CA, 1992 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - "Artes Festival to Open," Nuestro Tiempo section of the LA Times, photocopied article, 1991 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - "Chicano Art Hits Town," CARA review, SF Chronicle, 1992 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - "Women of Color contend with political, personal art," review, San Antonio Light, ca. 1991 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - "Images of Chicana Artists," review of "Artistas Chicanas" exhibit at UC Santa Barbara, Santa Barbara News-Press, 3/31/1991 (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - "War Paint - Artists respond to War," review of exhibit at the Mexican Museum, Artweek, San Jose, CA, 2/7/1991 (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - "Chicano Artists Paint for Peace," article in the Guardian, San Francisco, 1/30/1991 (Box 73, Folder 13)
  - "Mixed Blessings - New Art in Multicultural America," review of Hernandez's work, Pantheon Press, NY, 1990 (Box 73, Folder 14)
  - "Pride of the Mission - San Francisco's Latino artist community," SF Examiner, 5/20/1990 (Box 73, Folder 15)
  - "Wildly Colorful Latino Designs in Self Help Graphics Show," article, LA Times, 11/25/1989 (Box 73, Folder 16)
  - "The Goldies - Outstanding Local Discoveries," (1st Annual in the Guardian, San Francisco, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 17)
  - Dual Exhibits dedicated to "La Reina de Las Americas," review, River City Review, Austin, TX, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 18)
  - Galeria de la Raza - article, Northern California Home and Garden, November, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 19)
  - "The Defiant Eye - Ester Hernandez," Galeria de la Raza, monograph, announcement, invite, June 1988 (Box 73, Folder 20)
  - "Turquoise and Coral- Alice Walker," article in This World, San Francisco, 5/7/1989 (Box 73, Folder 21)
  - "Alternative to What?," review of San Francisco Arts Commision Gallery exhibit, Artweek, San Jose, CA, 8/20/1998 (Box 73, Folder 22)
  - "Brava!," Newsletter for women in the arts, July, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 23)
  - "Ester Hernandez," review of "Defiant Eye," El Mensajero, San Francisco, July, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 24)
  - "Arte Chicana - La icongrafia de la auto determinacion, raza, etnia y clase," Arte en Columbia, No. 34, 9/1987 (Box 73, Folder 25)
  - Latina Art:Showcase '87: brochure, Mexican Fine Arts Center Museum, Chicago, 1987 (Box 73, Folder 26)
  - Latina Art:Showcase '87:review, New Art Examiner, Chicago, 1987 (Box 73, Folder 27)
  - "Waiting for Eternity," review of Latina Art: Showcase '87, Reader, Chicago, 1987 (Box 73, Folder 28)
  - "Chicana Artist Ester Hernandez - Her Art Stirs Feeling for the Plight of Humanity," article, La Ventana, Sonoma County's Hispanic Newsletter, May/1987 (Box 73, Folder 29)
  - Freedom Notes: newsletter of the Dennis Banks Defense Committee, San Francisco, June - September, 1986 (Box 73, Folder 30)
  - Amanecer Indio - publicacion oficial de la confederacion de nacionalidade indigenas de la amazonia ecuatoriana, decembre, 1986 (Box 73, Folder 31)
  - "Mural Mural on the Wall - SF Art Institute," review of the Murals Project: Out of Context, The Daily Californian, Berkeley, 11/21/1986 (Box 73, Folder 32)
  - "An Inside Look Four Outdoor Murals," review of Murals Project: Out of Context, SF Examiner, 11/14/1986 (Box 73, Folder 33)
  - "Cinco de Mayo - a case of identity," article, Oakland Tribune, 5/5/1986 (Box 73, Folder 34)
  - South and Central American Indian Information Center (SAIIC): newsletter, Berkeley, CA, Spring, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 35)
  - "Chicanas Speak Out," review of Chicana Voices and Visions at SPARC [Social and Public Arts Resource Center], Artweek, San Jose, CA, 1/14/1984 (Box 73, Folder 36)
  - "Decontaminating Amerika - The Art of Ester Hernandez," interview published in Revista Literaria de El Tecolote, San Francisco, December, 1982 (Box 73, Folder 37)
  - "De Colores," article regarding Hernandez's mural project with senior citizens in Oakland, CA, The Montclarion, 6/28/1983 (Box 73, Folder 38)
  - "Oakland Seniors Unveil a Wall of Color," article regarding Arts Council mural project, SF Examiner,7/1/`983 (Box 73, Folder 39)
  - En Frequencia: monthly bi-lingual magazine and program guide for KBBF, Snta Rosa, CA, December 1979, January 1980: la Virgen and Libertad controversy (Box 73, Folder 40)
  - "Artists Finish Hispanic Mural," article, Oakland Tribune, 8/29/1980 (Box 73, Folder 41)
  - "Walls with Tongues...," article in Dutch regarding Chicano mural movement, Intermediair, Amsterdam, Holland, October, 1979 (Box 73, Folder 42)
  - "Oakland's ColorfulFederally-Funded New Street," article, Oakland tribune, ca. 1978 (Box 73, Folder 43)
  - "The Artists and Their Work - The Role of the Chicana Artist," article, Chismearte, Los Angeles, 1977 (Box 73, Folder 44)
  - "La Escuelita Teaches Unique Children's Art Class," article by Alicia Bustos,7/20/1977, El Mundo...[?], Oakland, CA (Box 73, Folder 45)
  - Indigena - News from Indian America, Berkeley, CA, Fall, 1976; graphics by Hernandez (Box 73, Folder 46)
  - "Ester, Lupe, Y La Chicana en el Arte," review article, La Razon Mestize, San Francisco, 1976 (Box 73, Folder 47)
  - "Women," article on the San Francisco Art Festival, SF Chronicle, 9/18/1974 (Box 73, Folder 48)
  - "A Mural is painting Done on Walls by Human Hands,"review of Mujeres Muralistas, El Tecolote, San Francisco, 9/18/1974 (Box 73, Folder 49)
  - "The Art of Ester Hernandez," article in Diatribe: People of Color News Collective, May, 1993 (Box 73, Folder 50)
  - La Raza Women's Seminar: Chicanas and Latinas in the US, San Francisco State University course reader, Fall, 1994 (Box 73, Folder 51)
  - "Salad Bar," Bayview Opear House at Hunter's Point, exhibit catalog, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 52)
- Art Business, Series 8; .5 linear ft.
  Mailing lists, bills of sale, price lists, artist's statements, biographical sketches, resumes, and other material concerning Hernandez's professional business relations are found in Series 8.
  - Mailing Lists (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Bill of Sale Receipts: miscellaneous (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Post/note cards, tee shirts accounts information: miscellaneous receipts, order forms, etc. (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Resumes: 1983-1999 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Biographies (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Letterheads (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Website Stickers (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Price Lists for Artwork (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - Artist Statements (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Business Cards (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Mural Projects: general information (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - Interview: Hernandez interviewed by H. Hyder, ca. 1983 (Box 74, Folder 12)
- Art Organizations, Series 9; 3 linear ft.
  Series 9 holds correspondence, loan agreements, exhibit catalogs, announcements, grant applications and reports, and other material from the many galleries, educational organizations, workshops, and conferences with which Hernandez maintained a professional relationship.
  - American Indian Community House, Inc., New York, NY (Box 75, Folder 1)
    Opening the Window - Examining the Border, 1997. Featuring the work of Ester Hernandez, Santa Barraza, Elvira and Hortensia Colorado, etc. Performance by Guillermo Gomez-Pena. Invitation, newsletter, correspondence, agreements, etc.
  - American Indian Contemporary Arts (AICA) and Galeria de LA Raza (Box 75, Folder 2)
    Indigenous Peoples: No Boundaries - Galeria de La Raza and AICA quincentennial collaboration - correspondence, exhibit info, reviews, brochures, magazine, invitation, etc. 1992.
  - Arizona State University, Hispanic Research Center - "1848/1898 @ 1998 - Transhistoric Thresholds" (Box 75, Folder 3)
    Conference regarding the historical consequences of the treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo and the Spanish American War. Slide lecture by Ester Hernandez and Gilberto "Magu" Lujan. Ester Hernandez' work is also part of the Chicano and Latino art exhibit. Correspondence, agreements, program, folio, flight and lodging information, etc.
  - Arizona State University, Hispanic Research Center: lecture, lithograph (Box 75, Folder 4)
    Ester Hernadez commissioned to lecture and create a lithograph in conjunction with Segura Publishing Co., Tempe AZ. Correspondence, contracts, catalog, receipts, flyers, etc., 1998.
  - Bakersfield Art Foundation (Box 75, Folder 5)
    Los Californios art exhibit at the Cunniingham Memorial Gallery, 1990, agreements. Ester Hernandez was asked not to submit "Sun Mad" so as not to upset important board members and trustee who part of the agri-business community.
  - Brandywine Workshop, Philiadelphia, PA (Box 75, Folder 6)
    1996 Visiting Artist Fellowship to create and complete a lithograph. Correspondence, agreements, brochures, newsletters, catalog, etc.
  - The Bronx Museum of the Arts (Box 75, Folder 7)
    Talk Back! The Community Responds to the Permanent Collection, Part II, 1997. Correspondence, brochures, agreements, etc. "La Ofrenda" is part of the permanent exhibit.
  - California Arts Council (Box 75, Folder 8)
    Information regarding Ester Hernandez' variou artist-in-community residencies. Notes, contracts, grant information, evaluations, project descriptions, etc., 1970-80s.
  - California Printmakers Society (Box 75, Folder 9)
    Information regarding membership, newsletter, etc., 1994
  - Creativity Explored, San Francisco (Box 75, Folder 10)
    Ester Hernandez art instructor at this program for developmentally disabled adults. Miscellaneous articles, etc.
  - CSU - Stanislaus - "Valley Grown" (Box 75, Folder 11)
    Valley Grown - Mexican-American Visions and Voices from the Central Valley, 1998. Featuring the work of Ester Hernandez, Ricardo Favela, Lorraine Garcia-Nakata, Louis "The Foot" Gonzalez, Jose Montoya, Malquillas Montoya, Ernest Palomino, Celia Rodriguez, Gary Soto, Estaban Villa, etc. Catalog, announcement, correspondence, etc.
  - Centro Cultural La Raza (Box 76, Folder 1)
    Information regarding the "GOP" [Graficas, Obras, Politicas] ehibition and problem with return of work, 1996.
  - CreArte, Minneapolis, MN (Box 76, Folder 2)
    Dia de Los Muertos exhibit - Ester Hernandez, featured artist, 1996. Correspondence, contracts, brochures, poster, etc.
  - Galeria de La Raza, 1980s (Box 76, Folder 3)
    Art activities, miscellaneous correspondence, announcements, flyers, reviews, newsletters, poster, etc.
  - Galeria de La Raza, 1990s [1 of 2] (Box 76, Folder 4)
    Art activities, miscellaneous correspondence, flyers, reviews, newsletters, etc.
  - Galeria de La Raza, 1990s [2 of 2] (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Galeria de La Raza "Defiant Eyes" (Box 76, Folder 6)
    Defiant Eyes - Works by Ester Hernandez, miscellaneous information regarding Ester's one person exhibited, curated by Amalia Mesa Baines, with a Chicana artists forum including Yolanda Lopez, Lorraine Garcia, Patricia Rodriguez, etc. Announcement, agreements, reviews, etc., 1988.
  - Galeria Posada "Day of the Dead" (Box 76, Folder 7)
    Miscellaneous information regarding Day of the Dead exhibit, art sales information and artist statement from 1980 Personal Relection exhibit.
  - Galeria Posada "Reflecting Connections" (Box 76, Folder 8)
    Reflecting Connections - Works on Paper exhibit with Native American artist Jean LaMarr and Ester Hernandez, curated by Tere Romo. Miscellaneous correspondence, agreements, announcement, etc.
  - Galeria de La Raza, "A traves de la Frontera" (Box 76, Folder 9)
    Collaboration with CEESTEM (Center for Economic and Social Studies of the Third World, Mexico City, 1981. Correspondence, poster (designred by Rupert Garcia), catalog, loan form, etc.
  - CN Gorman Museum, UC Davis (Box 76, Folder 10)
    Native American Studies exhibit, "The Art of Provocation - Ester Hernandez" - a retrospective, 1995. Curated by Teresa Harlan, catalog with statements by Dolores Huerta and Alice Walker and essay by Amalia Mesa-Baines. Catalog, announcement, miscellaneous correspondence, contracts, reviews, visitor responses, etc.
  - Guadalupe Cultural Arts Center [1] (Box 77, Folder 1)
    Located in San Antonio, TX. Miscellaneous correspondence, call for entries, etc.
  - Guadalupe Cultural Arts Center [2] (Box 77, Folder 2)
    Located in San Antonio, TX. Information regarding "Contemporary Art By Women of Color" exhibit and symposium, featuring the work of Ester Hernandez, Dolores Guerrero Cruz, Hung Liu, Barbara Jaramillo, Delilah Montoya, and others. Keynote address by Lucy R. Lippard, with speakers: Amalia Mesa-Baines, Rina Swentzel, Yong Soon Min, and Judith Wilson. Miscellaneous correspondence; program; black and white photo of Kathy Vargas (curator), unknown woman, Ester Hernandez, Pedro Rodriguez (ex. director), Hung Liu, and Lucy Lippard; newsletter; folio, etc.
  - Lab Ova (Box 77, Folder 3)
    Located in Yokohama, Japan. "The White Project:" visiting artist at Creativity Explored where Ester Hernandez orientated and assisted with their needs during their visit, 1998.
  - Lab Ova: Art Lab Ova workshop report, spring 1999, VHS cassette;" Soupy," Kuri Suzuki, Ring Records #QRI-01, compact disk, 1995 (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Laney College (Box 77, Folder 4)
    Laney College Art Gallery. "the Power of the Aztec Moon: Ester Hernandez - a Retrospective" exhibit in 1996. Miscellaneous information, announcement, correspondence, reviews, 5 color photos taken during slide lecture by artist. (Anna Montano - curator).
  - MACLA [Movimiento de Arte y Cultura Latino Americana] (Box 77, Folder 5)
    San Jose Center for Latino Arts exhibit "Transformation: The Art of Ester Hernandez," 1998. Curated by Holly Barnet, Ph.D. Miscellaneous correspondence, contracts, listrs of works, price lists, flers, invite, listings, comments from visitors, catalog with essay by Holly Barnet. Also miscellaneous information regarding MACLA.
  - Mexican Fine Arts Center Museum [1] (Box 77, Folder 6)
    Chicago, IL, Sor Juana Festival, etc. 1980s-1990s. Miscellaneous activities, reviews, programs, correspondence, agreements, etc.
  - Mexican Fine Arts Center Museum [2] (Box 77, Folder 7)
    Chicago, IL, exhibit "Art of the Other Mexico - Sources and Meanings," curated by Renee Arceo-Frutos, Juana Guzman, and Amalia Mesa-Baines. National and Mexico City venue. Includes work of Ester Hernandez, Margaret Garcia, Rupert garcia, Carmen Lomas Garza, Luis Jiminez Jr., Cesar Martinez, Celia Alvarez Munoz, Marcos Raya, Patricia Rodriguez, Peter Rodriguez, Rubin Trejo, John Valadez, Patsi Valdez, etc. Includes: catalog, announcement fronm several venues, reviews, miscellaneous correspondence, agreements, etc. 1992-93.
  - Mexican Fine Arts Center Museum [3] (Box 77, Folder 8)
    Dia De Los Muertos, 1989. Invitations, catalog, receipts, program, agreements, artist statement notes, list of installation artists.
  - The Mexican Museum [1] (Box 78, Folder 1)
    San Francisco, CA. miscellaneous information: correspondence, announcements, agreements, etc.
  - The Mexican Museum [2] (Box 78, Folder 2)
    San Francisco, CA, touring exhibit "Ceremony of Spirit: nature and Memory in Contemporary Latino Art," curated by Amalia Mesa-Baines, 1992. Miscellaneous correspondence, invites from the various venues, agreements, insurance value forms, reviews, etc. Exhibitors included: Ester Hernandez, Santa Baraza, Josely Carvalho, David Zamora Casas, Jonas dos Santos, Arturo Lindsay, Aida Mancillas, Cesar Agusto Martinez, Pepon Osorio, Marcos Raya, Patssi Valdez, Regina Vater, and others.
  - The Mexican Museum [3] (Box 78, Folder 3)
    The Fifth Element - Recent Acquisitions of Contemporary Chicano Art, 1992-93. Exhibit and two installations in progress with Enrique Chagoya and Ester Hernandez. Acquisition list includes print from the National Chicano Screenprint Taller, 1988. Miscellaneous correspondence; photocopy of reception list with artists and friends, including Ester Hernandez, Daniel Galvez, Carmen Lomas Garza, Patssi Valdez, Gronk, Amalia Mesa-Baines and other; folio, etc.
  - The Mexican Museum [4] (Box 78, Folder 4)
    Retablos en Aztlan: Images of Cultural Homage exhibit, 1991. Artists include: Ester Hernandez, Patssi Valdez, Santa Barraza, etc. Reviews, miscellaneous correpsondence, invitations, etc. This exhibit was intended to be a one person exhibit by Santa, but she did not have enough work completed, so others were invited to participate.
  - The Mexican Museum [5] (Box 78, Folder 5)
    Lo Del Corazon - Hearetbeat of a Culture exhibit, 1996. Featured are: Alfredo Arreguin, David Avalos, Judith Baca, Amalia Mesa-Bains, Santa Barraza, Enrique Chagoya, Ricardo Favela, Rudy Fernandez, Harry Gamboa, Eva Garcia, Carmen Lomas Garza, Ester Hernandez, Juan Alicia, Luis Jiminez Jr., Yolanda Lopez, Gilbert "Magu" Lujan, Irene Perez, Celia Rodriguez, Patricia Rodriguez, Larry yanez, Rene Yanez, etc.
  - Mission Cultural Center (Box 78, Folder 6)
    Rooms for the Dead, 1990 exhibit in San Francisco, curated by Rene Yanez. Announcement - Renee Moreno on the cove, face painted by Ester Hernandez.
  - Mission Cultural Center, San Francisco (Box 78, Folder 7)
    Miscellaneous programs, etc.
  - El Museo Del Barrio, New York, NY (Box 78, Folder 8)
    Miscellaneous information.
  - Museo de Gravura, Citidade de Curitiba, Brazil (Box 78, Folder 9)
    X Mostra da Gravura/Mostra America exhibit, 1992. Also sponsored by the Fundacao Cultural de Curitiba. Miscellaneous correspondence, agreements, shipping information, catalog, etc.
  - National Latino Communications Center (NLCC), Los Angeles, CA (Box 78, Folder 10)
    Chicano! History of the Mexican American Civil Rights Movement video series, 1990s. Ester Hernandez interviewed, and reproduction of artwork in two segments of series. Miscellaneous correspondence, agreements, releases, programming guide, brochures, poster, reviews, receipts, announcements, invoices, photocopies from Ester Hernandez' family archives, PR materials, etc.
  - The Oakland Museum [1] (Box 78, Folder 11)
    Vida y Muerte: Day of the Dead exhibit, 1994. Miscellaneous correspondence, invoices, reviews, magazine, artists statements and notes, invitations, etc.
  - The Oakland Museum [2] (Box 78, Folder 12)
    Dia de Los Muertos: Ancient Roots and Evolving Traditions exhibit, 1998. Curated by Tere Romo. Featured installations by: Ester hernandez, Consuelo Jiminez Underwood, and others. Miscellaneous correspondence, invoices, agreements, catalog, poster, invitations, etc.
  - La Pena, latino Arts in Austin, Austin, TX (Box 78, Folder 13)
    "Women of Hope" exhibit, March -April 1999: confirmation correspondence, agreement, newsletter, etc.
  - Posada de Colores, Oakland (Box 78, Folder 14)
    Ceramic Sculpture exhibit, works by Visata College Arts and Crafts Class, Ester Herandez, instructor [n.d.]
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, New York, NY (Box 79, Folder 1)
    Ester Hernandez Preliminary and Final reader for the PACT (Partnerships Affirming Community Transformation) program. Correspondence, brochures, grant applications, rating information, etc., 1996.
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, New York, NY: (Box 97, Folder 4)
    Ester Hernandez Preliminary and Final reader for the PACT (Partnerships Affirming Community Transformation) program. TCP/IP connection disk, 3.5" diskette, Apple
  - San Francisco Museum of Modern Art (Box 79, Folder 2)
    Information regarding CARA [Chicano Art - Resistance and Affirmation] and the National Chicano Print Taller acquisition, correspondence, 1995
  - Self Help Graphics, Los Angeles, CA (Box 79, Folder 3)
    Miscellaneous correspondence, reviews, postcards, catalogs, reviews, agreements, exhibit reports, certificate of authenticity -print documentation, etc. 1980-90s.
  - Serpent Source Foundation, San Francisco (Box 79, Folder 4)
    Submission form for grant.
  - Social and Public Arts Resource Center (SPARC), Venice, CA [1] (Box 79, Folder 5)
    Micellaneous corespondence, reviews, catalog reproductions, etc., 1980-90.
  - Social and Public Arts Resource Center (SPARC), Venice, CA [2] (Box 79, Folder 6)
    Borders, Barriers and Beaners - Attacking the Myths, 1998 exhibit. Ester Hernandez installation: "Immigrant Woman's Dress." Other artists include Judy Baca, David Botello, Yreina Cervantez, Margaret Garcia, Wayne Healy, leo Limon, Yolanda Lopez, Amalia Mesa-Baines, etc. Miscellaneous correspondence, agreements, reviews, artist statement, packing instruction, installation instructions, miscellaneous notes, sketches, etc.
  - Smithsonian Institute, National Museum of American Art [1] (Box 79, Folder 7)
    Miscellaneous correpsondence regarding their acquisition of artwork by Ester Hernandez, etc., 1990s.
  - Smithsonian Institute, National Museum of American Art [2] (Box 79, Folder 8)
    Posters American Style traveling exhibit,1998-1999. Ester Hernandez' "Sun Mad Raisins" included in collection, along with the works of Richard Avedon, Rupert Garcia, Rick Griffin, Dorothea Lange, Roy Lichtenstein, Victor Moscoso, Stanley Mouse, Georgia O'Keefe, Maxfield Parrish, Edward Penfield, and others. Miscellaneous correspondence, invitations, artist's release, photographs, etc.
  - Stanford University [1 of 2] (Box 80, Folder 1)
    Miscellaneous project information (Chicana Art Archive, Cesar Chavez week poster, etc.), agreements, newsletters, invoices, poster designs, etc., 1990s.
  - Stanford University [2 of 2] (Box 97, Folder 5)
    Miscellaneous project information (Chicana Art Archive, Cesar Chavez week poster, etc.) Zip drive, Apple format, Adobe Illustrator files, 1990s
  - Stanford University:The Lecture by Ester and Ann, audio cassette, 1/28/1999 (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Tanpopo-No-Ye, Nara, Japan (Box 80, Folder 2)
    Information regarding Ester Hernandez (as a professional artist and Creativity Explored art teacher) lecture and tour of Japan. In particular, talking to volunteers who will work with people with disabilities. Miscellaneous correspondence, slides of Creativity Explored, audio cassette, etc., 1999.